<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Rostgaard.IT</title>
	<subtitle>Crypto &amp; IT.</subtitle>
	<link href="https://blog.rostgaard.it/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://blog.rostgaard.it/"/>
	<updated>2020-11-17T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
	<id>https://blog.rostgaard.it/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Mark Rostgaard</name>
		<email>mrostgaard@protonmail.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>About me and what i offer (working title)</title>
		<link href="https://blog.rostgaard.it/posts/me-as-a-post/"/>
		<updated>2020-11-17T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>https://blog.rostgaard.it/posts/me-as-a-post/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;For a smaller introduction to me and a look at contact details, please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rostgaard.it/&quot;&gt;frontpage.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;About me&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Mark, I&#39;m 27 years old, I live in Copenhagen and works as a software developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have experience with quite a few different programming paradigms and languages. My primary tools for development is Python and React.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have a few years experience with Blockchain technology. I&#39;ve written my masters about Ethereum&lt;sup&gt;[&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.rostgaard.it/files/Thesis.pdf&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/sup&gt;, I&#39;ve worked over a year for Bitcoin Suisse and I&#39;ve cofounded, and also volunteered in, Nordic Blockchain Association.
    I&#39;ve also had some speaking about Bitcoin and blockchain technology, more details can be found &lt;a href=&quot;#speaking&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve worked as a consultant, where I&#39;ve implemented different software solutions, amongst these are some bank compliance software for Googles technology stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Experience and what i&#39;m offering&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a understanding that most people, will not know, or care of, technical details of my expertise. For this reason the details can be found the &lt;a href=&quot;#details&quot;&gt;headline below.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I offer a variaty of services. Mostly i like to create things and working with new technologies, so if you have a project you might think I can help with, don&#39;t hesistate to contact me and we can have a non-committal conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have extensive experience in building backend and frontend software. One of my greatest enjoyment is to create beautifull frontends, that is user engaging and friendly to use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can setup and work with the most common database system and I have experience working with servers, mostly Linux based. If you want your system to run on AWS services it is also something i have some experience with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can talk about Blockchain technology for days, so if you have an interest in this or would like me to talk at a conference, or maybe your collegues, about blockchain, what it is and if this is something that&#39;s right for your company, I can help with that &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;details&quot;&gt;Technical details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have years of experience working full stack, juggling between a beautifull and easy to use frontend, and a powerfull backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my backend experience is either in Python with Django or C# with the Entity Framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;gdc&quot;&gt;For Python some of the projects I&#39;ve worked on includes:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;An Investment portfolio tracker&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A Google Drive compliance tool&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Web Portal to manage security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
I&#39;ve also created the frontends for these projects in React.

&lt;h4&gt;Some of the C# projects I&#39;ve worked on includes:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A Crypto Payment system&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;An abstraction layer for easy communication with multiple blockchains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Blockchain&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a great interest and expertise with Blockchain Technology. Ranging from a high theoretical understanding of the technical components, all the to the financial incentives and game theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than the projects I&#39;ve worked on as a part of my employment at Bitcoin Suisse, I&#39;ve also done some academic work in that capacity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Build a Bitcoin like blockchain in Python&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Researched how to use Blockchain to decentralize Certificate Authorities&lt;sup&gt;[&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.rostgaard.it/files/Thesis.pdf&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bitcoin Suisse&lt;/h2&gt;
After my employment at Bitcoin Suisse i received this letter of &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.rostgaard.it/files/BTCS-anbefaling.pdf&quot;&gt;recommendation.&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Consulting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tricent&lt;/h3&gt;
For Tricent i developed a Security Web Portal and the Google compliance software as mentioned &lt;a href=&quot;#gdc&quot;&gt;above&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;h4&gt;Google compliance software&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tricent.com/&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is the project as it looks now. I was hired by them in the beginning of 2019, so it has obviusly changed since.

&lt;h2 id=&quot;speaking&quot;&gt;Speaking&lt;/h2&gt;
As a part of my volunteer work in Nordic Blockchain Association I&#39;ve talked to a few different people and companies.
&lt;h3&gt;Nordic Blockchain Association Conference&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a part of the Technical side of this conference, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/u53ENtWgffQ?t=64&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;I spoke&lt;/a&gt; about blockchain and gave a short introduction to how Bitcoins blockchain protocol work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This presentation have been used and updated since and I&#39;ve used this to succesfully explain Bitcoins blockchain in both professional and &#39;casual&#39; settings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these places have been: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Crypto Bar&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;NNIT&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&#39;Master Group&#39; meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;CV: &lt;/h2&gt;
My cv can be viewed on the index page, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.rostgaard.it/#cv&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; will take you there.

</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
